"Take your brolly, it's chucking it down!"
"带上你的雨伞，下大雨了！"
The UK is famous for its rainy weather, and Brits LOVE to complain about it – particularly when the arrival of spring teases us with warmth and light, but with them come the 'April showers', lovingly shared by Britain, Ireland and some of coastal northern Europe.
英国以其多雨的天气而闻名，英国人喜欢抱怨它——尤其是当春天的到来用温暖和阳光撩拨我们时，但随之而来的是"四月阵雨"，这雨在英国、爱尔兰和北欧部分沿海地区很常见。
What exactly are they, and why do they insist on coming every year?
它们到底是什么，为什么每年都非要来？
Meteorologists differentiate between rain and showers.
气象学家将雨和阵雨区分开来。
The UK's national weather service, the Met Office, says that rain is precipitation brought by a weather front, is usually long-lasting, and stretches over large areas, whereas showers fall from individual clouds and are characterised by intermittent patterns.
英国国家气象局表示，雨是由天气锋面带来的降水，通常持续时间长，覆盖范围广，而阵雨则来自单独的云团，其特点是间歇性模式。
So, it can be sunny one minute, and the next you're getting caught in a large downpour, but then ten minutes later, you can put away your waterproof jacket and get your sunnies out!
所以，前一分钟还是晴天，下一分钟你就被大雨淋湿了，但十分钟后，你就可以收起防水夹克，拿出太阳镜了！
So, what's responsible?
那么，是什么原因造成的呢？
Rob Thompson, meteorologist at the University of Reading, says that as the hot air rises, it forms the cumulus clouds that produce showers.
雷丁大学气象学家罗布·汤普森说，随着热空气上升，形成产生阵雨的积雨云。
These are then driven by the jet stream – strong winds that move northwards during spring – creating rather unsettled and unpredictable weather.
这些云随后被急流驱动——春季向北移动的强风——造成了相当不稳定和不可预测的天气。
Besides the drizzle, we're just as likely to experience snow as we are to feel sun as strong as that in late August!
（四月）除了毛毛雨，我们既有可能感受到八月底那样强烈的阳光，也同样有可能下雪！
With all this in mind, would it surprise you to hear that April is actually one of the driest months of the whole year?
考虑到这些，听到四月实际上是一年中最干旱的月份之一，你会感到惊讶吗？
In 2021, data company Statista recorded 137.6mm of rainfall in January, compared to just 20.1mm in April, with similar results for the last four years.
2021年，数据公司Statista记录了一月份137.6毫米的降雨量，而四月份仅为20.1毫米，过去四年的结果也类似。
That's because while there are lots of rainy days in April, the showers are scattered, and there aren't as many of the long downpours we see in the winter months.
这是因为虽然四月雨天很多，但阵雨是分散的，而且不像冬季月份那样有那么多长时间的倾盆大雨。
But, this is likely to change as the world warms up.
但是，随着全球变暖，这种情况可能会改变。
Weather that causes flash floods is predicted to be four times as frequent in Britain by the 2070s, according to a study by Elizabeth Kendon and colleagues, published in Nature Communications.
根据伊丽莎白·肯登及其同事发表在《自然通讯》上的一项研究，到21世纪70年代，英国引发山洪暴发的天气预计将增加四倍。
There is a British proverb that goes "March winds and April showers bring forth May flowers".
有一句英国谚语说："三月风，四月雨，带来五月花。"
It is a reminder that, despite our complaints, April showers can be a symbol for renewal and new beginnings.
这提醒我们，尽管我们抱怨，四月阵雨也可以是更新和新开始的象征。
So Brits, instead of complaining about the drizzly days, why not romanticise that pitter-patter sound that brings us the colourful spring bloom?
所以英国人，与其抱怨细雨绵绵的日子，为什么不把带来绚丽春色的雨滴声浪漫化呢？